miniclips.biz 2014-12-23

# Privacy Policy - Miniclip, Play Games

## Miniclip Privacy Policy

Last updated: 26th June 2013

Miniclip is committed to providing fun and exciting digital entertainment across all its products and services, such as Miniclip.com (and its related sub-sites) and all applications available on smartphone devices, tablets, browser and desktop (together, the " **Services** "). Miniclip.com is the property of Miniclip SA (" **Miniclip** "). Miniclip respects the privacy concerns of all users of its Services. Miniclip does not target its Services to users under the age of 13, but does take measures to help protect the privacy of those who are.

**By using the Services you agree to observe and be bound by this Privacy Policy and you consent to the processing, collection, use and disclosure of your information and data in accordance with its terms. Please do not use the Services if you do not agree to this Privacy Policy.**

In this Privacy Policy 'non-personal data' means data we may collect from you but which does not identify you directly. This data may be 'aggregated' with other data to help us improve our Services and otherwise in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

### Children's privacy

We take special precautions respecting users under the age of 13. If a user chooses to register, they can input a date of birth, username and email address to set up an account. The under-13 user's account is limited to participating in those aspects of the Services that are deemed to be appropriate for users under 13; features of our Services that may involve the possibility of posting personal information, such as comments, are automatically disabled.

Immediately upon registration, the under-13 user's email address is turned into an encrypted format, a "one way hash", which we can't read and which is used to authenticate the user login process.

We do not permanently store the email addresses of users under 13 in a recoverable format and, because we do not retain the email addresses of under-13 users in a usable form after initial registration, we have no means of initiating contact with such users by email after registration. The user name of registered users under 13 is not used as a means to contact such users.

We do not collect more personal data than is necessary to respond to a question or one-off request from a user under 13, to provide parental notice or to obtain parental consent, nor do we distribute to third parties any personal information collected from children known to be under 13 without parental consent. Parents are invited to review their children's information by contacting us as described below.

### Information we collect

If you are **13 years of age or older** and you choose to register to use the Services we will collect your date of birth, username, password and email address and we may collect other information such as your smartphone device type. We may also collect non-personal data from registered users. For instance, we may collect data relating to registered users' use of the website and the Services, as well as that relating to their activities, such as high scores, game rankings, league rankings, game challenges, avatars etc. We may log IP addresses and drop cookies or flash cookies to support the internal operations of the Services, such as to prevent abuse of the Services or to provide and/or enhance them. Please note that IP addresses, if logged, are neither stored nor linked to any user account.

We may also collect anonymous, statistical data from users of the Services, such as a user's browser version, operating system version, country, page loading time, type of device, number of visits, time using the Services, network, demographic estimates, flow-through the website and/or Services or referral source, which may then be aggregated. We may use non-personal data that we collect from you to improve the Services or to support advertising services. For registered users, this anonymous, statistical data may include that relating to their activities, such as high scores, game rankings, league rankings, game challenges, avatars etc.

### Facebook Connect

If you register to use the Services via Facebook Connect, a service which you need to be over 13 years of age to use, you give us express permission to receive data from Facebook such as your name, user ID, gender, location (country and/or city specific), email address, date of birth and avatar. For Facebook Connect users we store the following information: user ID, first name, email address, date of birth, gender, avatar and other information based on your use of our Services. Your email address and the access token (by which Facebook grants us permission to access certain information) are encrypted.

### Making purchases through the Services

If, as a registered user, you choose to purchase any items while using the Services on Miniclip.com or elsewhere, we will be able to access your payment information which is collected by our payment processing providers who ensure your credit card information is encrypted. Miniclip does not store your credit card information.

### On mobile

When using our smartphone applications certain features like our newsfeed may collect additional non-personal data from you including, without limitation, device, platform, hashed MAC address, device operating system version and/or generated device identifier information; this data is used to support internal operations only. We may collect country and/or city information so that we can send push notifications at more convenient times. If you would like to opt out of these notifications, you can disable notifications to the relevant app using the settings in your smartphone. Please contact [support@miniclip.com](mailto:support@miniclip.com) for more information on how to control access to your information.

### Information that is reasonably necessary

Miniclip does not require users under 13 years of age to disclose any more information than is reasonably necessary to use the Services and/or as a condition of participation.

### How we use and disclose the information

We do not retain any personal data for longer than necessary. We may use information to ensure that users are in compliance with our terms. By using the Services and agreeing to this Privacy Policy, users over 13 years of age authorise us to use their information for our general commercial purposes including to send email, SMS or other notifications to them relating to the Services.

We may sometimes use information that we collect to improve the design and content of the Services, to customize our Services or to personalise our visitors' experience or to offer products, advertising, programs and services. We may also use this information in the aggregate to analyse usage of the Services or to offer products, programs, or additional services.

Miniclip may disclose information to third parties in special cases, such as (1) when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with Miniclip's property, visitors, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities or to comply with the law, applicable regulations, governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders or subpoenas; (2) our agents, outside vendors or service providers to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing customer service, processing orders, etc.); (3)when the information is provided to help complete a transaction for you; (4) if the disclosure is done as part of a purchase, transfer or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, customer information may be one of the transferred assets); or (5) as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

### Collection of Information by Third-Parties and Sponsors; Opting Out

We do not disclose personal data of users under 13 years of age to any third parties. We use Google Adsense and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads and/or provide aggregated data to assist in serving ads when you visit Miniclip.com. We use web analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to analyse the use of the Services. Miniclip may use information about your use of the Services in order to provide advertisements for goods and services that may be of interest to you. We may also share non-personal information that we collect from you with our business partners or clients so that they may improve their services. Third party companies, including those whose games run on Miniclip.com, may ask for information from you which would be governed by the privacy policy of such companies; in which case they should provide adequate disclosure of their privacy policies to you. We advise you to take care when any company or third party game provider asks you to input personal data. Third parties (including ad networks, ad exchanges, advertisers and/or game developers whose games can be found on the Site but which are hosted on servers elsewhere) and/or Miniclip may be placing and reading standard and/or flash cookies on your browser and machine, or using web beacons to collect non-personal information in the course of your use of the Services. You may manage or opt out of your flash cookies by emailing support@miniclip.com. You may manage or opt out of your standard cookies via your web browser and if you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please email us at support@miniclip.com.

While using the Services you may be able to connect to social networking sites or find games and products of other companies. Please note that your use of these other companies' services, such as Facebook Connect or Club Penguin, will be governed by the relevant operator's terms and conditions and privacy policy.

### Deleting, amending or updating your data

If you would like to delete, amend or update your data or the way we may use it, including opting out of any marketing emails then please do email us at [support@miniclip.com](mailto:support@miniclip.com).

### Security

In our provision of the Services we have implemented appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorised access, maintain data security and correctly use the information we collect online.

We use industry-standard practices such as encryption, physically secured rooms, firewalls and password protection systems to safeguard the confidentiality of any personal information that we might collect from you. We also strive to limit access to personal information to employees performing a legitimate business function. We review our security procedures periodically to consider appropriate new technology and updated methods.

### Parental Review

Parents, if you would like to review your child's information, ask to have it deleted, and/or refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child's information, then please send a letter to our Privacy Manager at Miniclip S.A., Rue des Beaux-Arts 8, 2000, Neuchâtel, Switzerland. Please be sure to include your email address and a telephone number where we can reach you. Our phone number is +41 327 235902. To protect your child's privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting you access to the information that we collect and maintain about your child.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy; Contacting Us

This Privacy Policy is part of Miniclip's Terms and Conditions to which you agree by using the Services, including accessing the Miniclip.com website. You agree that Miniclip may change this Privacy Policy and the Miniclip Terms and Conditions at any time. Our current Privacy Policy will be posted here: <http://www.miniclip.com/privacy> as part of our Terms and Conditions which you can find here: <http://www.miniclip.com/games/page/en/terms-and-conditions>. Our contact email for questions is: [support@miniclip.com](mailto:support@miniclip.com). Or you can write to us at Miniclip S.A., Rue des Beaux-Arts 8, 2000, Neuchâtel, Switzerland.

### Internet Safety

Miniclip recommends that parents take time to communicate and educate their children about Internet Safety. Please see the Miniclip Internet Safety webpage for information on Internet Safety: <http://www.miniclip.com/games/page/en/internet-safety/>
